Armand G. Winfield Papers
Armand G. Winfield Papers
1957-1991
Winfield, Armand G.
29.75 linear ft.
Collection contains the professional and personal papers of Armand G. Winfield. It focuses on the client files of Winfield's consulting company, which he formed in 1964.
2651183
Biographical History
Armand G. Winfield (1919-2009) was an American inventor, researcher, and educator in the field of plastics.
Armand G. Winfield was born December 28, 1919. He graduated from Franklin & Marshall College in 1941. During his junior and senior years, Winfield was named an assistant in the Geology Department and Assistant Curator of the school's museum. He attended field sessions in anthropology at the University of New Mexico in the summers of 1939 and 1940. While in the army, he created fake wounds for training soldiers. After he was discharged, he returned to museum work.
In 1945, Winfield founded Winfield Fine Art in Jewelry in New York City, with his brother. He invented the first mass-production method of embedding objects in clear acrylics creating one-of-kind original wearable works of art. Winfield would embed the art, shape it and then convert it into the actual piece of jewelry. Some of this jewelry has ended up in galleries and collections, including the archives of The Smithsonian Institute's Museum of American History in Washington, DC (1988), and the National Design Museum; the Cooper-Hewitt Museum in New York City (1994); the Royal Science Museum, and the National Historic Plastics Museum, both in London; and in the Center for Southwest Research in Albuquerque, New Mexico and the National Plastics Center in Leominster, Massachusetts.
Winfield attended graduate school at Washington University, St. Louis, Missouri, 1948-1950, and went on to hold a succession jobs in the plastics industry. From 1957 until 1963, he worked as Plastics Consulting Engineer at DeBell & Richardson Inc., in Hazardville, Connecticut. During his years at DeBell, he taught as a plastics engineer in Yale's School of Art in New Haven in 1960-1961.
In 1964, Winfield started his own company, consulting in plastics research and development until 1994. During this time he became involved in designing and directing the construction of 13 separate installations for the New York World's Fair. These projects included the American Express Outdoor Map of the World, the General Electric VIP pavilion, a portion of the Singer Sewing Machine Exhibit and a number of sets for Leon Leonidoff's WonderWorld Productions.
He began teaching at the Pratt Institute in New York in 1964 and became a consultant and instructor at the Institute's School of Industrial Design in Brooklyn, New York. That led to his appointment as a Visiting Critic in Architecture for plastics at the College of the City of New York (CCNY) a few years later.
Winfield took an interest in the use of plastics in building and construction and in 1968 he was awarded a grant by the United Nations Industrial Development Organization (UNIDO) and assigned to survey the use of plastic materials for housing in developing countries. Following his survey, in 1971 Winfield was invited to present an updated study for UNIDO on the “Uses of Plastics in the Building Industry” in Vienna, Austria.
In May of 1971, Winfield and his wife Barbara, who was also his business partner, were invited to Sydney, Australia where he gave a lecture on “Plastics in Building” and on “The Use of Plastics as Low Cost Housing Potentials” at the Second Australian Symposium on Reinforced Plastics and Composites.
His work on the use of plastics in housing led him to work on creating soft surfaces for the elderly and infirm in housing. In 1971, he was issued a patent on his work. He authored “The World's First Soft Bathroom” and “Impact Absorbing Laminate and Articles Fabricated There From.” C.A.R.E. Inc. retained Armand's firm in 1972 to design, develop and produce a low-cost prototype house for Bangladesh, India, primarily using jute as the building material along with polyester binders.
Winfield obtained a U.S. Patent No. 3,819,466, “Reinforced and Insulating Building Panel” and assigned it to the C.A.R.E. organization. The house became known internationally as the C.A.R.E./Bangladesh/Winfield house and stood on Long Island weathering for 18 years.
Relative to his work in housing, Winfield made his way to Santa Fe in 1979 and to the College of Santa Fe in New Mexico. In 1984, Winfield and his wife hosted five students form the Armand Hammer United World College of the American West, Montezuma, New Mexico. Then, in 1993, Winfield was appointed Director, and became the founder of the University of New Mexico's New Training and Research Institute for Plastics (TRIP). He served as Director of the Institute until April, 2004, when health problems forced his retirement.
He is the author of nearly 350 published articles, chapters and books on plastics and related subjects. He lectured all over the world and worked tirelessly to educate young people. In 1983, he was elected to the Plastics Pioneers Association in recognition of the service.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Armand G. Winfield Papers contains the professional papers and some personal papers of Armand G. Winfield. It focuses on the client files of Winfield's consulting company which he formed in 1964 with his wife, Barbara.
Client folders contains all of Winfield's numbered client files.
Miscellaneous client folders includes business dealings with clients not numbered.
Papers contains "100 Years Young," by Winfield, professional and personal communications and finances, printed material, newspaper and magazine clippings, and two VHS tapes.
Arrangement of the Collection
Collection is divided into the series listed above and alphabetized.
Related Material
has numerous holdings in the areas of plastics and industrial design. Please refer to for a complete listing. See also the Armand G. Winfield Collection, Cooper-Hewitt Museum and the Smithsonian Institution's National Museum of Design, New York; and the Armand G. Winfield Papers at the Center for Southwest Research, University of New Mexico.
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; Industrial Design; Plastics; Winfield, Armand G.; Bristol-Myers Co. Ltd.; College of Santa Fe.; Foster Grant (Firm) -- Archives.; Hallmark Cards, Inc.; Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.); Pratt Institute. School of Art and Design.; Santa Fe Chamber of Commerce (Santa Fe, N.M.); Society of Plastics Engineers.; United Nations Industrial Development Organization.; Antiques.; Plastics in building.; Plastics industry and trade.; Plastics -- Research.; Plastics as art material.; Colombia.; Santa Fe (N.M.).; Catalogs (documents); Correspondence.; Business papers.; Newsletters.; Research notes.; Technical reports.; Technical drawings.; Businessmen.; Consultants.; Inventors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Transfer from National Plastics Center and Museum, 11/06/2008.
Originally, gift of Armand G. Winfield in memory of Barbara LaBarge Winfield, 2004
Inventory
- Client folders
  - #236-237, 244-245, 251, 257-258, 260-266, 268-271, 273-283, 285, 287-288, 296-297, 315-316, 318-319, 326-329, 331-334, 336-337, 339-350, 352-355, 363-393 - missing when received, 2/2009
  - 3M (#84), 1968-1970; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Airco (Air Reduction Co.) (#128), 1971 (Box 1)
  - Alix Antiques (#168), 1974; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Alumet Corporation (#124), 1971; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - American Aniline & Extract (#12), 1964 (Box 1)
  - American Cyanamid Company (#14), 1964 (Box 1)
  - American Engineering Model Co. (#173), 1975 (Box 1)
  - American Institute of Architects Journal (#25), 1964-1970 (Box 1)
  - American Marble Products Co. (#16), 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - American Museum of Natural History (#305) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - Amtech Corporation (#307), 1985; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Anderson, John (#324), 1987 (Box 2)
  - ANTEC embedments (#67) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - Anton Products Corporation (#46), 1966-1967 (Box 2)
  - Applied Training Dynamics (#298, 310): billing, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Applied Training Dynamics (#298, 310): communications, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Applied Training Dynamics (#298, 310): drawings, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Applied Training Dynamics (#298, 310): financial information, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Applied Training Dynamics (#298, 310): general, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Applied Training Dynamics (#298, 310): patents, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Applied Training Dynamics (#298, 310): pro-forma, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Applied Training Dynamics (#298, 310): trips, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Applied Training Dynamics (#298, 310): miscellaneous, 1982-1983; 1985-1986; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Applied Training Dynamics (#298, 310): miscellaneous, 1984-1987; 7 folders (Box 4)
  - Applied Training Dynamics (#298, 310): miscellaneous, 1985-1986; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Architectural Engineering News (#32), 1965 (Box 5)
  - Arman (#27), 1964-1970; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Armen Inc. (#68), 1969-1975 (Box 5)
  - Armoni, Ziva (#51), 1967 (Box 5)
  - Artistic Latex Foam Co. (#40), 1964-1967; 1971; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Attwood Products Inc. (#140), 1972 (Box 5)
  - Bachman, John (#359) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - Backe, Lief (#294), 1985 (Box 5)
  - Bangor Punta Operations Inc. (#131), 1970-1971; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Barbara Day Company (#335), 1984-1985; 1987-1988; 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Bassine, Buelah (#88), 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - BDF (Black Development Foundation, Inc.) (#144), 1972-1973; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Bedding Magazine (#135), 1971-1972; 1974; articles submitted (Box 6)
  - Bendix Corporation (#220), 1980 (Box 6)
  - Bilkays Express Co. (#145), 1972 (Box 6)
  - Blackman, Andrew S. AIA (#200), 1978-1980; 7 folders (Box 6)
  - Blackman, Andrew S. AIA (#200), 1978-1979; 7 folders (Box 7)
  - Blackman, Andrew S. AIA (#200), 1979; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Blackman, Andrew S. AIA (#200), 1979; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Borrego, James (#325), 1986-1987 (Box 8)
  - Brewster Corp. (#58), 1971-1972; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Brit. Newf. Exp. Ltd (#43) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - Bristol-Myers Co. (#126), 1971-1975 (Box 8)
  - Book, Lubin (#66) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - Brookville Country Club (#65) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - Brown, Harry L. (#11), 1964 (Box 8)
  - Brzezinksi, Zbigniew (#101), 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Burden, William (#93), 1969-1975; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Burden, William (#93), 1969-1975; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Burden, William (#93), 1969-1674; 12 folders (Box 10)
  - Business Communications Co. (#150), 1973 (Box 11)
  - Butchkeys, Sydney (#73), 1968 (Box 11)
  - Cahn Conveyor Systems, Inc. (#161), 1973-1975 (Box 11)
  - California Polytechnic State Univ. (#221), 1980 (Box 11)
  - CARE Inc. (#139), 1972 (Box 11)
  - Carlisle Jewelry (#240) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - Castelli Industries (#208) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - Cavrock Manufacturing Co. (#2), 1964-1967 (Box 11)
  - CCNY visiting critic (#76), 1968-1969 (Box 11)
  - Cerro Corporation (#29), 1964-1965; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Chalem, Celine (#54), 1967 (Box 11)
  - Chavez, Fabian (#243), 1981 (Box 11)
  - Chavez, Tino key tags (#256), 1982 (Box 11)
  - Chemspec (#190) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - Chirug & Cairns embedment (#108), 1970 (Box 11)
  - Citizens for Eric Scrua (#253) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - Civerolo, Hansen & Wolf (#291), 1982-1983; 1985 (Box 11)
  - Civerolo, Hansen & Wolf (#291), 1982-1985; 8 folders (Box 12)
  - Clark, Keith R. (#30), 1965 (Box 13)
  - Club of Sante Fe (#241), 1981 (Box 13)
  - Cochiti Puebo (#230), 1981 (Box 13)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): advertising contracts, 1980 (Box 13)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): agenda, 1980 (Box 13)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): art work and layouts, 1980 (Box 13)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): clippings, 1980; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): committee members, 1980 (Box 13)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): communications, 1980; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): conference updates, 1980 (Box 13)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): contacts, 1980 (Box 13)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): contacts, 1980; 3 folders (Box 14)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): entertainment, 1980 (Box 14)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): final report, 1980 (Box 14)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): forums, 1980 (Box 14)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): moderators, 1980 (Box 14)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): news release, 1980 (Box 14)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): press, 1980 (Box 14)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): program, 1980 (Box 14)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): publicity, 1980; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): publicity, 1980 (Box 15)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): speakers, 1980; 20 folders (Box 15)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): speakers, 1980; 5 folders (Box 16)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): special: Limpkins, William, 1980 (Box 16)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): speeches, 1980 (Box 16)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): field trip, 1980 (Box 16)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): field trip hosts, 1980; 3 folders (Box 16)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): registrations, 1980; 3 folders (Box 16)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): special invitations to opening, 1980 (Box 16)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): UNIDO, 1980 (Box 16)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): miscellaneous, 1980; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - College of Santa Fe Energy Conference (#214): miscellaneous, 1980; 4 folders (Box 17)
  - College Plastics Lab (# 233), 1975-1978; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Columbus Enterprise (#97) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - Commercial Fiberglass (#209) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - Congoleum Industries (#90), 1966; 1969-1970,; 1972,; 1974; 3 folders (Box 17)
  - Conrad, Terry (#311), 1985-1986 (Box 18)
  - Construction Specifications Institute (#100), 1969-1970 (Box 18)
  - Cooper Union (#81), 1968-1969 (Box 18)
  - Corchia, deHarak (#120), 1970-1971 (Box 18)
  - Creative Marketers Company (#147), 1972 (Box 18)
  - Cross Island Electric Corp. (#197), 1975-1978 (Box 18)
  - Dake Corporation (#175), 1973 (Box 18)
  - David Hamberger Inc. (#155), 1973-1974 (Box 18)
  - Davis, Arley E. (#228), 1981; 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Davis Fitzhugh Irrigation Systems (#141), 1972; 2 folders (Box 18)
  - DD Manufacturing Group (#196), 1977-1978 (Box 18)
  - DeMartin, Marona, Cranstoun, Downes (#170), 1974 (Box 19)
  - Dennis Larkins Studio (#309), 1985 (Box 19)
  - Dillon, Jay (#289), 1984-1985; 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Display World (#15), 1964-1968; 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Divigioz, Solan (#225) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - Dixon, W.N. (#312), 1985-1986 (Box 19)
  - Dome East (#179), 1975 (Box 19)
  - Eastland, James (#202), 1978 (Box 20)
  - Eder, Earl (#259), 1982 (Box 20)
  - Electronized Chemical Corporation (#26), 1965-1966 (Box 20)
  - Elektra Corporation (#89), 1969 (Box 20)
  - Eli Ask-Elan Assoc. (#83) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - Elliot Lee Inc. (#56), 1967 (Box 20)
  - Emhart Corporation (#37), 1965-1966; 1974 (Box 20)
  - Emanuel, Deetjen & Co. (#64), 1967-1968 (Box 20)
  - EMS Sales Group (#129), 1971 (Box 20)
  - Enfield Manufacturing (#180), 1975; 3 folders (Box 20)
  - Enfield Manufacturing (#180), 1975-1976; 3 folders (Box 21)
  - Environmental Graphics Inc. (#143), 1972 (Box 21)
  - Evenflo (#117), 1971; 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Extrudyne (#127), 1971-1975 (Box 21)
  - Finders Delightful (#184), 1975-1976; 3 folders (Box 21)
  - Finders Delightful (#184), 1975-1976 (Box 22)
  - Fine Arts Foundation (#42), 1966 (Box 22)
  - Flexabar (#111), 1969-1970 (Box 22)
  - Foster Grant (#149): billing, 1973-1975 (Box 22)
  - Foster Grant (#149): final report, 1972 (Box 22)
  - Foster Grant (#149): general correspondence, 1972-1975; 3 folders (Box 22)
  - Foster Grant (#149): general correspondence, 1974 (Box 23)
  - Foster Grant (#149): myriad, 1975-1976; 6 folders (Box 23)
  - Foster Grant (#149): Nichrome, 1974 (Box 24)
  - Foster Grant (#149): oven file, 1972-1976; 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Foster Grant (#149): pencil, 1974 (Box 24)
  - Foster Grant (#149): proposal and contract, 1973 (Box 24)
  - Foster Grant (#149): retainer, 1973-1975 (Box 24)
  - Foster Grant (#149): silo file, 1974-1975; 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Foster Grant (#149): Sinn file, 1969 (Box 24)
  - Foster Grant (#149): trips, 1974; 5 folders (Box 24)
  - Foster Grant (#149): trips, 1973-1975; 19 folders (Box 25)
  - Foster Grant (#149): miscellaneous, 1968; 1972-1974; 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Frank, Bryan L. (#323), 1986-1987 (Box 26)
  - Frank Yu Fiberoptics (#320), 1986-1987 (Box 26)
  - Franklin & Marshall College (#232), 1975-1978 (Box 26)
  - Freidman, John (#99), 1969-1970 (Box 26)
  - Frohlich, Fred - proquinal (#322), 1986-1987 (Box 26)
  - Futuro Corp. (#86), 1969-1971; 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Garcia, Anthony (#227) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - General Electric Co. (#159), 1973 (Box 26)
  - Glas-mate (#125), 1971 (Box 26)
  - Glaser, Milton (#74), 1968 (Box 26)
  - Gleason Works (#166), 1974 (Box 27)
  - Goose-in-the-Bottle Construction Co. (#218), 1980-1981 (Box 27)
  - Gorgeous Lamp Co. (#121), 1971 (Box 27)
  - Greene Plastics Co. (#45), 1965-1967; 1973-1975 (Box 27)
  - Greneker Co. (#9), 1964 (Box 27)
  - Grippi, Joseph (#53), 1967 (Box 27)
  - Grow West Hydroponics (#213) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - Gruber Systems (#210), 1979 (Box 27)
  - Gunnar, Birkerts & Associates (#112), 1970-1971; 5 folders (Box 27)
  - Gunnar, Birkerts & Associates (#112), 1970; 3 folders (Box 28)
  - Hackett, Dwight/Hanbury, Una/Art Foundry (#219), 1980 (Box 28)
  - Hallmark (#39): 1776 project, 1973 (Box 28)
  - Hallmark (#39): 3d, 1973 (Box 28)
  - Hallmark (#39): acrylic embedment procedures, 1975 (Box 28)
  - Hallmark (#39): billings and statements, 1973-1975 (Box 28)
  - Hallmark (#39): carousel file, 1974-1975 (Box 28)
  - Hallmark (#39): clear injection molding, 1972 (Box 28)
  - Hallmark (#39): die cutting block, 1972 (Box 28)
  - Hallmark (#39): educational trips, 1966-1967 (Box 29)
  - Hallmark (#39): embedment projects, 1973-1975 (Box 29)
  - Hallmark (#39): extrudyne, circa 1970 (Box 29)
  - Hallmark (#39): general, 1972-1975; 3 folders (Box 29)
  - Hallmark (#39): light box display, 1972 (Box 29)
  - Hallmark (#39): potential licensees, 1972 (Box 29)
  - Hallmark (#39): press manufacturing co., 1973 (Box 29)
  - Hallmark (#39): puzzles: foams (ethafoam, Sekisui, etc.), 1972 (Box 29)
  - Hallmark (#39): recruiting, 1965 (Box 29)
  - Hallmark (#39): retainer, 1972-1973; 2 folders (Box 29)
  - Hallmark (#39): RF Co., 1974 (Box 29)
  - Hallmark (#39): Rhodes, Jack, 1972 (Box 29)
  - Hallmark (#39): survey - machinery, 1981-1983; 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Hallmark (#39): survey - molders (Germany and England), 1982 (Box 30)
  - Hallmark (#39): survey - tooling, 1981-1982; 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Hallmark (#39): typed final pages, 1983 (Box 30)
  - Hallmark (#39): trips, 1971-1974; 4 folders (Box 30)
  - Hallmark (#39): trips, 1972-1973; 3 folders (Box 31)
  - Hallmark (#39): "up stuff" line, 1972 (Box 31)
  - Hallmark (#39): urea foam dunnage, 1972 (Box 31)
  - Hallmark (#39): WEP line, 1972 (Box 31)
  - Hallmark (#39): writing instruments, 1974-1975 (Box 31)
  - Hallmark (#39): miscellaneous, 1967-1974; 1978; 6 folders (Box 31)
  - Hallmark (#39): miscellaneous, 1965-1967; 1969-1971; 7 folders (Box 32)
  - Hallmark (#39): miscellaneous, 1970 (Box 33)
  - Hammett, Kinglsey H. (#223), 1980 (Box 33)
  - Hammond Industries (#255) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - Hayloft Thrift Shop (#113), 1970-1971 (Box 33)
  - Heather High Times (#215), 1980; 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Hidalgo, Steve (#216) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - Higgins, Richard (#102) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - Hitchcock, Ray (#160), 1973 (Box 33)
  - Holt, Rinehart & Winston, Inc. (#136), 1972 (Box 33)
  - I Catchers/LaPiccolo, Anna (#182), 1974-1975 (Box 33)
  - IDCL Canadian project (#152), 1975 (Box 33)
  - ILLI, Inc. (#98), 1970-1971 (Box 33)
  - Industrial Plastics Industrial Consultants (#59), 1967-1968; 1971; 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Inner-Active Development, 1985; 1987; 2 folders (Box 34)
  - International Development Consortium (#152), 1972-1975; 5 folders (Box 34)
  - Instant Worm (#204), 1978; 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Item Processing Systems (#330), 1987-1988 (Box 35)
  - Japanese Reinforced Plastics Org. (#172), 1974-1975 (Box 35)
  - Jerry Roth Associates (#13), 1965 (Box 35)
  - Jewelite Co. (#1), 1964 (Box 35)
  - Joe Carr's Washers (#239), 1981 (Box 35)
  - Kimberling, Janet W. (#321), 1986 (Box 35)
  - Kiwanis (#234), 1981 (Box 35)
  - Knoebels Groves (#176), 1975 (Box 35)
  - KOL Inc. (#181), 1975 (Box 35)
  - Koretz, Willa (#351), 1990 (Box 35)
  - LA Darling Co. (#36), 1965 (Box 35)
  - LaBarge (#71), 1968-1970; 2 folders (Box 35)
  - LaMar Plastics Packaging Ltd. (#146), 1972 (Box 36)
  - Lassonde Plastics Ind. (#49), 1966-1967 (Box 36)
  - Lee Bee Metals (#158), 1973 (Box 36)
  - Lienau, David (#338), 1988 (Box 36)
  - Lincoln, JD (#358), 1990 (Box 36)
  - Liza, Mara (#85), 1970 (Box 36)
  - Locite (#306), 1985 (Box 36)
  - Madrid Mining Town Museum (#290), 1983-1985; 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Maisano, Louis (#194), 1977 (Box 36)
  - Mallory, Ron (#24), 1964 (Box 36)
  - Manley, Marion B. (#75), 1968 (Box 36)
  - Martin Shippers Supply, Inc. (#317), 1987 (Box 36)
  - Master Appliance Corp. (#169), 1974-1977 (Box 36)
  - Materie Plastiche, 1971-1974 (Box 37)
  - Matheson, Robert (#183), 1975-1978; 3 folders (Box 37)
  - Merit Abrasive Products, Inc. (#174), 1974 (Box 37)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art (#107), 1964-1965; 1970; 4 folders (Box 37)
  - Met Opera (#118), 1971-1972; 1974 (Box 37)
  - Mittens Designer Letters (#31), 1965 (Box 37)
  - Modern Plastics magazine (#8), 1964-1965; 1971-1973; 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Morland Products (#63), 1968-1969 (Box 38)
  - Mulhauser, George (#48), 1966 (Box 38)
  - Murphy, Señor (#229) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - Museum of Modern Art (#156), 1973 (Box 38)
  - Museum Scope (#187), 1976-1977 (Box 38)
  - Nally Ltd. (#122), 1971; 3 folders (Box 38)
  - Nambe Mills (#246), 1981 (Box 38)
  - National Carousel Roundtable (#165) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - National Sculpture Center (#103), 1970-197; 2 folders (Box 38)
  - National Tractor Pullers Association (#199), 1978 (Box 38)
  - Naumberg, Judy (#295), 1985 (Box 38)
  - NBC embedments (#23), 1964 (Box 38)
  - New Mexico Engineering Research Institute (#286), 1983-1984 (Box 38)
  - New Mexico Engineering Research Institute (#286), 1983 (Box 39)
  - New Mexico Prison Industries (#284), 1983-1984 (Box 39)
  - NEUF (#135), 1971-1974 (Box 39)
  - Newberger, Babette (#70), 1968-1969 (Box 39)
  - Jean Nicolesco, Jean (#91) - missing when received, 2/2009
  - Norfield (#167): client literature, circa 1975 (Box 39)
  - Norfield (#167): general correspondence, 1975; 2 folders (Box 39)
  - Norfield (#167): Long Island, 1975 (Box 39)
  - Norfield (#167): prices, 1975 (Box 39)
  - Norfield (#167): sales development, 1975 (Box 39)
  - Norfield (#167): testing, 1974 (Box 39)
  - Norfield (#167): trips, 1974; 9 folders (Box 39)